KARANJOT SINGH SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PERSONAL INFO

Address: Arlington, TX Email: <u>Karan.nanda97@gmail.com</u> Mobile: 682-313-4726 Linkedin: <u>karanjotsingh1995</u> Portfolio: <u>karanjot1995.github.io</u> Github: <u>Karanjot1995</u>

SUMMARY

Full stack software developer with over 4 years of experience in PHP, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Reactjs, Python, SQL and various other languages. Results-driven, customer focused, strong in design/development and integration problem solving skills with multiple full stack application deliveries within the years.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Megger (Dallas, Tx): Software Engineer

July 2023 - Current

- Functioned and designed Megger web portal(demoassets.com) for handling equipment delivery, management and tracking using PHP Laravel, Vuejs, Javascript and MySql and deployed on AWS.
- Singlehandedly took care of all the processes from design and development to testing.
- Building the rental platform using Vuejs and built RESTful APIs using PHP Laravel to serve the data stored in MYSQL db. This is helping the company cut the cost for paid platforms by almost 75%.

Megger (Dallas, Tx): Software Engineer Intern

June 2022 - May 2023

- Functioned and designed Megger web portal(demoassets.com) for handling equipment delivery and management using PHP Laravel, Vuejs, Javascript and MySql.
- Validated, tested and wrote code to maximize the performance and deliver the best in a short period of time.

Collegedunia web pvt ltd (collegedunia.com): Software Engineer

March 2021 - August 2021

- Worked with collegedunia.com from March 2021 to August 2021 as a senior software engineer on their main education portal(collegedunia.com) and led
 a team of 10 using Nextis, Reactis, Nodejs, HTML and CSS.
- Defined and conducted the project on various stages including research, conceptualization, testing and implementation and Created many components like dynamic forms, search etc. and APIs.
- Achieved a 15% reduction in software development cycle time by optimizing the deployment pipeline and implementing automated testing.

Hogarth Worldwide, India: Software Engineer

July 2018 - March 2021

- Led a team for 4 for Discernliving.com website using technologies like Reactjs (javascript framework), Nodejs, Expressjs, HTML and CSS.
- Developed and Maintained BMW India website as a team lead on AEM Platform and used HTML, CSS and javascript for development. Increased user engagement by 15% through the implementation of responsive design and interactive user interfaces.
- Developed a Workplace Management Tool for the company for timesheet management, HR management and employee management and cut down
 employee management time by a significant 60% using Reactjs javascript framework, Redux, Nodejs, Express and Mongodb.
- Achieved a 20% improvement in website loading speed by optimizing frontend code and implementing caching strategies.
- Automated the SEO process by creating an SEO Tool using Reactjs javascript framework, Redux and Nodejs.

CERTIFICATIONS

Coursera Meta Front-End: React, Javascript, Version Control, HTML & CSS in Depth

EDUCATION

The University of Texas At Arlington: M.S. Computer Science – Aug 2021- May 2023 Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University, Delhi: B.Tech Electronics and Communication Engineering

SKILLS

Reactjs, Redux, Vuejs, MongoDb, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Nodejs, Express, Python, Angularjs, GraphQL Flask, Django, HTML, GIT, Java, PHP, Laravel, Rest API, TypeScript, AEM, CSS, REACT NATIVE, jQuery, AWS, Google cloud platform(GCP), Selenium, Azure, Kubernetes, Docker, Jenkins, Firebase, Passportjs, Azure, SQL, Sitecore, Sass, Bootstrap, Web Development, Android/ios app development, UI-UX Mobile Devices & Applications, Adobe Photoshop, Wordpress

OTHER PROJECTS

Used concepts of Digital Image Processing along with languages like C++ to create an application that has image and video capturing capabilities, manipulating image windows, handling track bars and mouse events etc

Using technologies like React Native, Python and SQL for android app development, created a Book Management System.

Made various projects like Netflix(clone), Workplace Management Tool, groomers.in, socialweb, SEO Tool, authentication, to-do-list using Mysql, MongoDB, Express js, React js, Nodejs and various other static templates using HTML, CSS and JS.

Developed various static designs like facebook-design using HTML, CSS and Javascript showcasing the focus on intricate details.